Xingjian Zhen

Department of Computer Science, University of Wisconsin-Madison 5770B Medical Science Center. Madison, WI, 53705 xzhen3@wisc.edu

[Homepage] [Github]

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interest is about different structured data for medical application in Computer Vision. Since it's quite mature for Euclidean space machine learning, I would like to explore some different structured data or constrained data. For example, the Symmetric Positive Definite matrix in medical data (DTI) or covariance matrix are the data with constraint. I want to try some neural networks in Euclidean space, and extend them to the structured data, manifold data as an example, to do the classification or regression. I believe this will be useful in diagnosis from a medical perspective or analysis of the video/image information.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Student, Department of Computer Science UW-Madison, WI, U.S. B.E., Department of Electronic Engineering

August 2013 - July 2017

August 2017 - present

Tsinghua University, Beijing, P.R. China.

Paper

- Rudrasis Chakraborty, Chun-Hao Yang*, Xingjian Zhen*, Monami Banerjee,
 Derek Archer, David Vaillancourt, Vikas Singh, Baba C. Vemuri. "A Statistical
 Recurrent Model on the Manifold of Symmetric Positive Definite Matrices." In
 Thirty-second Annual Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems
 (NeurIPS), 2018
- Xingjian Zhen, Rudrasis Chakraborty, Nicholas Vogt, Seong Jae Hwang, Sterling C. Johnson, Barbara B. Bendlin, Vikas Singh. "Group Analysis for PiB Status with Sequential Deep Learning Model on DTI." Alzheimer's Association International Conference (AAIC), 2019
- Xingjian Zhen*, Rudrasis Chakraborty*, Nicholas Vogt, Barbara B. Bendlin, Vikas Singh. "Dilated Convolutional Neural Networks for Sequential Manifoldvalued Data." IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2019
- Xingjian Zhen*, Han Yang*, Ying Chi, Lei Zhang, Xiansheng Hua. "CPR-GCN: Conditional Partial-Residual Graph Convolutional Network in Automated Anatomical Labeling of Coronary Arteries." In submission

RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

Group Analysis for PiB Status with Sequential Deep Learning Model on DTI 01/2019-03/2019

• Used Ants as registration tool to warp information from template space into subject space

- Extracted each voxel along each fiber bundles in DTI space to fit the sequential model
- With PiB status as group, found 2 fiber bundles satisfying significance level

Dilated CNN in Group Analysis of Alzheimer's Disease 08/2018-12/2018

- Pre-processed the dMRI to extract the information of fiber bundles
- Applied SPD/ODF Manifold into Dilated CNN model to directly extract information from DTI/ODF
- Speed up the training and testing model with competitive number of parameters with the state of the art
- With CSF and APOE biomarkers, got statistically significant results on several fiber bundles

Statistical Recurrent Model on the Manifold

01/2018-05/2018

- Defined the operator in the manifold space
- Applied SPD manifold into statistical recurrent model
- Significantly reduced the number of parameters of the video classification model
- Used this model to achieve the state of art of accuraccy in UCF11 dataset

Correlationship for Image-Text Pair in Latent Space 09/2017-01/2018

- Applied the pre-trained CNN as the feature extractor from image side
- Applied the word2vec method on text as the representive of sentence
- Used t-SNE to minimum the KL divergence between latent space and the Image-Text pair
- Got meaningful result for the local dataset

Form Line Detection in the Picture

12/2016-06/2017

- Developed a system that detects and recognizes the form lines in pictures
- Used the bidirectional RNN method to achieve the state of the art, with MXNet as the core of the deep-learning system
- Tested in multiple databases such as the NIST Special Database 2 and got a high accuracy rate

INTERN EXPERIENCES

DAMO Academy, Alibaba

05/2019-09/2019

- Research intern in DAMO Academy Medical AI Algorithm Research, Alibaba
- Developed an automated anatomical labeling of coronary arteries via CPR-GCN
- Used 3D-CNN with BiLSTM to extract the features from the CT images along branches
- Used both image domain and position information with the partial-residual connection to achieve 95.8% mean recall

COMPUTER SKILLS

Deep learning framework: PyTorch, TensorFlow

Languages: Python, C++, Matlab Softwares: Visual Studio, Matlab